<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The opinions of the Barons of the Exchecquer. And directions to all justices of the peace, and constables, &amp;c. for the legally convicting of all persons, that are taken in conventicles, and unlawful meetings. Given at the Court of Exchecquer, upon Justice Balch's case. Published by special authority.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Court of Exchequer.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1682</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B27628</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing O358</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 515.l.2[58]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R213297</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99884081</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99884081</idno>
            <idno type="VID">189553</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B27628)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 189553)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C17:1[59])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The opinions of the Barons of the Exchecquer. And directions to all justices of the peace, and constables, &amp;c. for the legally convicting of all persons, that are taken in conventicles, and unlawful meetings. Given at the Court of Exchecquer, upon Justice Balch's case. Published by special authority.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Court of Exchequer.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet (2 p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for R.H. and are to be sold by Walter Davies, in Amen-Corner, near Pater-Noster-Row,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1682.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Dissenters, Religious --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:189553:1"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:189553:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>THE OPINIONS OF THE <hi>Barons of the Exchecquer.</hi> AND DIRECTIONS TO ALL Juſtices of the Peace, AND CONSTABLES, &amp;c. For the Legally Convicting of all Perſons, that are taken in Conventicles, and un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lawful Meetings.</head>
            <head type="sub">
               <hi>Given at the Court of</hi> Exchecquer, <hi>upon Juſtice</hi> Balch's <hi>Caſe.</hi>
            </head>
            <floatingText type="license" xml:lang="eng">
               <body>
                  <p>Publiſhed by Special Authority.</p>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <p>THe <hi>Juſtices of Peace of Middleſex</hi> having a good while ſince received His Majeſties Orders in Council, to put the Laws in Execution, and to Suppreſs <hi>Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venticles;</hi> ſome of the ſaid <hi>Juſtices</hi> accordingly iſſued out their Warrant to Mr. <hi>Hodges,</hi> a Conſtable, requiring him to Suppreſs the <hi>Conventicle</hi> kept by One Dr. <hi>Anneſley;</hi> and to
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:189553:2"/>ſeize ſuch Perſons, as ſhould be found met there, upon pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence of a Religious Worſhip, contrary to Law: The ſaid Conſtable repairing thither, found above 200. Perſons ſo Aſſembled; One of whom being ſeized, and carried be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore Mr. Juſtice <hi>Balch,</hi> was (upon his refuſing to Declare his Name) Committed to Priſon: But ſometime after owning himſelf to be called <hi>White,</hi> and being thereupon Diſcharged, brought his Action of Two Thouſand Pound, for falſe Impriſonment againſt Mr. <hi>Balch,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Hodges.</hi> The Caſe being debated by Council Learned on both ſides, before the Barons of His Majeſties Court of <hi>Exchequer</hi> (the latter End of Laſt <hi>Terme</hi>) Verdict was given againſt the ſaid <hi>White,</hi> and he condemn'd in treble Coſts, as the Law directs: the <hi>Court</hi> further unanimouſly Declared the Law to be,</p>
            <p n="1">1. That if thoſe in a <hi>Conventicle</hi> refuſe to open the Door upon a Juſtice of Peace his Warrant, Entrance being de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded, the Door may be broken open.</p>
            <p n="2">2. That the Perſons apprehended there, are Convict<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed upon their being brought before a <hi>Juſtice of Peace,</hi> with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Oath; incurring the ſame <hi>Penalty,</hi> as if they were Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>victed by Oath; as the Law directs in ſuch Caſes.</p>
            <p n="3">3. That thoſe Perſons that are in <hi>Conventicles,</hi> though not brought before a <hi>Juſtice of the Peace,</hi> may notwithſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing be Convicted by the Oath of Two Witneſſes, of their being <hi>There;</hi> incurring alſo the ſame <hi>Penalty,</hi> as if they were; as the Law directs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="4">4. That if any Perſon ſo ſeized, denies his Name, he may be Committed to Priſon.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>R. H.</hi> and are to be Sold by <hi>Walter Davies,</hi> in <hi>Amen-Corner,</hi> near <hi>Pater-Noſter-Row,</hi> 1682.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
